welcome back to another audacity
欢迎回到另一个大胆的地方
tutorial in this video we're going to be
在这段视频中 我们将成为
playing with some different effects the
使用一些不同的效果
ones we're gonna do are changing the
我们要做的是改变
speed changing the tempo and changing
速度改变节奏和改变
the pitch so to get started let's go
球场 开始吧 我们开始吧
ahead and just let's record in some
接下来 让我们来录制一些
voice so that we can get a good idea for
这样我们就能有一个好主意
what's happening here this is test audio
这里发生了什么？这是测试音频
testing one two three
测试一二三
okay so now we have our audio in here if
好的 现在我们在这里有我们的音频 如果
we play it back that sounds just like it
我们回放它 听起来就像它
did when I said it so if we want to
当我说的时候 如果我们想的话
change the speed of this change it so it
改变这个速度 改变它 这样它
plays back faster that's kind of one of
回放更快 这是一种
the most common things first of all like
最常见的事情首先是
we learned in our last video we have to
我们在上一段视频中了解到 我们必须
make a selection so if we go to FX and
进行选择 这样如果我们转到FX并
go down to change speed we're gonna get
下去改变速度 我们将得到
this kind of an error message and just
这是一条错误消息 只是
saying or this dialog that says you need
说还是这个对话说你需要
to make a selection first we can press
要先进行选择 我们可以按
ctrl a to select all so ctrl a we can
按Ctrl a键选择全部 以便我们可以按Ctrl a键
also just select all by ourselves like
也只是自己挑选就好了
doing this do or we can just select any
执行此操作 或者我们可以只选择
portion that we want to increase the
我们要增加的部分
speed but I'm going to do select all
速度 但我要选择所有
this another way to do is go to select
另一种方法是选择
and then go to all and then we can go to
然后转到All 然后我们可以转到
effects and speed change speed and then
效果和速度改变速度 然后
this is sort of like we did with the
这有点像我们对
amplification we have a slider bar here
放大我们这里有一个滑动条
and we have some different numbers so if
我们有一些不同的数字 所以如果
we change the speed multiplier down to
我们把速度倍增调低到
zero again we're going to be Oh actually
再说一次 我们将成为哦 事实上
the percent change is zero if we change
如果我们更改 百分比变化为零
the percent this to zero and the speed
这个百分比是零 速度是
to one it's going to be same speed
对一个人来说 它的速度将是相同的
nothing will change so we do okay so
什么都不会改变 所以我们做得很好
that's kind of our baseline so knowing
这是我们的底线 所以我们知道
that we can change the speed to either
我们可以把速度改成
faster or slower to be either less than
比…更快或更慢
1 on the multiplier or more than 1 so if
乘数为1或大于1 则如果
we did 2 here it would be twice as fast
我们在这里做了2次 速度会快一倍
and it was so it would be 100% increased
因此 它将100%地增加
by 100% if we did 0.5 it would be 50% of
到100% 如果我们做0.5% 将是50%
normal speed so you can control either
正常速度 这样你就可以控制
one of these two boxes are linked so
这两个盒子中的一个是连接在一起的
let's just do this real quick let's do
我们就快点开始吧 我们开始吧
the 50% let's do it
那50%让我们开始吧
half as fast as this normally supposed
比通常假设的速度快一半
to be so we go okay and then we see what
所以我们走得很好 然后我们就会看到
first of all happened our first audio
首先是我们的第一段音频
recording was four seconds long or four
录音是四秒钟长或四秒
and a half I guess and now it's like
我猜是一半 现在就像是
nine seconds long because it's half the
九秒长 因为它是
speed so it takes twice as long to play
速度很快 所以玩起来需要两倍的时间
that so let's play and see so it's just
所以让我们拭目以待吧 所以
slow-motion like you would imagine
慢动作 就像你想象的那样
let's go undo we click this back arrow
让我们来撤消我们点击这个后退箭头
here or we can press ctrl Z on the
我们也可以在此处按Ctrl Z键
keyboard it's still selected so let's go
键盘它仍处于选中状态 因此我们开始吧
to FX change speed and now let's we can
FX改变速度 现在我们可以
type in if we want to do two but we can
如果我们想做两个 请输入 但我们可以
also use the slider to get it kind of a
也可以使用滑块将其设置为
more granular so let's go to let's do it
更细粒度 所以让我们开始吧 开始吧
about maybe one point seven six and then
大约一点七六 然后
we go okay so now you see it's almost
我们走得很好 所以现在你看 差不多了
instead of being four and a half seconds
而不是四秒半
it's only two and a half seconds so it's
只有两秒半的时间 所以
gonna be much quicker because it's
会快得多 因为它
playing faster so we'll play this and
玩得更快 所以我们要玩这个
you notice the pitch of my voice changed
你注意到我的音调变了吗？
to when it was long it was very low
当它很长的时候 它是非常低的
there's a lot lower because it's slowed
低得多 因为它慢了很多
down I guess what I'm saying is not only
我想我要说的不仅仅是
did it slow down the audio it also in
它是否放慢了音频的播放速度
the process lowered and raised the pitch
这一过程降低和提高了音调
of my voice so it's like high pitch now
我的声音所以现在就像是高音
and so the way we can change that if you
所以我们可以改变这一点的方法是 如果你
want to speed something up slightly but
想要稍微加快速度 但
you don't want to increase the the pitch
你不会想要增加音调的
maybe it's music need to throw off the
也许是音乐需要抛开
key
钥匙
let's go back the thing we can do is we
我们回去吧 我们能做的就是
can actually go to effects change tempo
可以实际转到效果更改节奏
and what that's going to do is change
而这将带来的是改变
the speed it's gonna change how quickly
它会改变的速度有多快
the file the wave is being played but
正在播放的WAVE文件
it's not going to adjust the pitch so we
它不会调整音高 所以我们
can select all of this let's go to
可以选择所有这些 让我们转到
control a to select all and let's go
按Ctrl a选择全部 然后开始吧
affect change tempo so now we can change
影响改变的节奏 所以现在我们可以改变
the tempo and have it be played one and
节奏 让它演奏一次 然后
a half times faster than it normally is
比平时快半倍
wait a percentage maybe this needs to be
等等 也许这需要
so actually let's play it 150 percent
所以实际上让我们玩150%
normal then it needs to be or than it
正常 那么它就需要比它更正常
was regularly and we click OK so now
是定期的 我们点击OK 现在
look it shrinks it down but now if we
听着 它缩小了它 但现在如果我们
play I don't think my voice will be
我想我的声音不会是
high-pitched
高音
you see so it's my my voice is the same
你看 这是我的 我的声音是一样的
pitch as it is now it's just playing
就像现在的投球一样 它只是在比赛
through much faster I'm gonna do control
通过更快的速度 我要做控制
Z I'm gonna do control C and control V
我要做控制C和控制V
so we have this twice and we're going to
我们有两次这样的机会 我们要
I'm gonna show them back-to-back so we
我要让他们背靠背地看 所以我们
see what's happening here let's go to
看看这里发生了什么 让我们去
effect change speed let's make this one
效果改变速度 让我们做这件事
1.5 or actually so we're doing the same
1.5或实际上我们也在做同样的事情
thing we'll make it a hundred and fifty
我们会达到150
percent and we or let's just make it a
% 我们或者让我们把它变成
hundred percent go okay and then let's
百分之百顺利 然后让我们
select this part I just double click on
选择我只需双击的这一部分
it to select just that area cuz see
它只选择该区域 因为请参见
there's look separation between them and
他们之间有一种看起来很分离的感觉
we go effects change tempo and it
我们走 效果改变节奏 它
changed this to one hundred and go okay
把这个改成100 然后就可以了
so now we can play these two and one is
所以现在我们可以玩这两个 第一个是
Jett they're both the same they both
杰特 他们都一样 他们都是
take about two seconds long to play but
大约需要两秒钟的时间才能玩完 但
one is gonna be a higher pitch you see
一个是更高的音调 你看
what I'm saying so they these both have
我想说的是 他们两个都有
the same tempo but they have a different
相同的节奏 但他们有不同的
pitch I'm gonna come to the end here and
我要在这里走到尽头
do control V and paste this file again
执行V键并再次粘贴此文件
this is the original again so if I
这又是原版 所以如果我
double click this and select it all we
双击此选项并将其全部选中
can go to effects and this third thing
可以转到特效和这第三件事
we can change is the pitch so if we
我们可以改变音调 所以如果我们
change the pitch of this we can actually
改变音调 我们实际上可以
change the pitch and make me talk in a
换个音调 让我用一种
different key so it's saying right now I
不同的密钥 所以它现在说的是我
don't know if this auto-detects I'm not
不知道这会不会自动检测到我没有
actually exactly sure but this is saying
实际上非常确定 但这是在说
change it from F so if any note if any
如果有音符 请将其从F改为
yeah basically if there's anything that
是的基本上如果有什么
was an F will get changed to down to AG
是F将改为向下改为AG
sharp or a flat if you're if you
如果你是尖锐的或平坦的 如果你
understand music and so what's going
懂音乐 所以这是怎么回事
down eight point eight four semitones
下降八点八四个半音
and so we can adjust this to or it's
所以我们可以把这个调整到或者它
also in so this is why do pitch this is
还有 这就是为什么要这样做的原因
everyone do frequency so it's changing
每个人都在做频率 所以它在变化
from a frequency of 50 500 Hertz down to
从50500赫兹的频率降到
a frequency of 3,300 Hertz and that
3300赫兹的频率
change represents roughly forty percent
变化约占40%
so you could imagine if we double click
所以你可以想象如果我们双击
and change this to zero this is neutral
把这个改成零 这是中性的
this is from the key of F to the key of
这是从F的键到键的
F this is from this Hertz to this source
F：这是从这个赫兹到这个信号源
which is the same so if
这是相同的 所以如果
want to make it a higher pitch we had
想要让我们有更高的音调
above zero we that this percent change
在零以上 我们认为这个百分比会发生变化
be above zero if I want to make it a
如果我想要使其成为
lower pitch this is below in the
较低的音调这是在
negative so let's let's make it let's
否定的 所以让我们来吧 让我们
just make my voice a tiny bit lower
只要把我的声音压低一点
let's go down let's go down like just
我们下去吧让我们下去就像这样
20% lower maybe like this
低20% 也许是这样
21% lower and okay so the speed is the
降低21% 还可以 所以速度是
same you see it didn't change the size
和你看到的一样 它没有改变大小
of this it's still lasting about four
其中 它仍然持续了大约四年
and a half seconds but it's going to be
一个半秒 但这将是
lower let's play and see if it sounds
放低一点 让我们来玩 看看它是不是听起来
different okay so I'm gonna undo that
不同的 好的 所以我要撤销它
let's now it's back to normal I can
我们走吧 现在一切都恢复正常了
double click and we can change the pitch
双击 我们就可以改变音高
again and we could this time we can make
再一次 我们可以 这次我们可以
it high we can make it be above zero so
它很高 我们可以使它在零度以上 所以
we come over here to above zero and
我们来到零度以上
let's make it 20% faster than it
我们让它比它快20%
originally was recorded in so we go okay
原来是录制的 所以我们走好了
all right so there we go we've got we've
好的 我们走吧 我们有 我们有
changed we can change the speed if we go
如果我们走了 我们可以改变速度
to effects change speed that changes how
效果改变速度 从而改变方式
quickly it's played or slowly it's
它要么很快播放 要么慢慢播放
played and it also changes the pitch so
它也改变了音高 所以
speed that does both speed is basically
这两个速度的速度基本上是
doing pitch and tempo at the same time
同时做音高和速度
pitch obviously just does the pitch that
显然 Pitch就是在做这个
if it's high or low and tempo just does
如果它是高的或低的 节奏就是这样
the speed and keeps the pitch constant
速度和保持俯仰恒定
so play with those three and then I want
所以玩这三个人 然后我想
to show you one more thing if we just go
再给你看一件事 如果我们走了
file new and we bring in this audio file
文件是新的 我们引入了这个音频文件
I'll go open this jazz guitar
我去打开这把爵士吉他
so suppose we know what key this is in
假设我们知道这是什么键
this this music
这是这首歌
let's say it's in the key of G maybe so
让我们假设它在G的基调中 也许是这样
if this is in the key of G and we want
如果这是G的基调 我们想要
to transfer we want to change this
要转移 我们想要更改此设置
someone sends us some music and they say
有人给我们寄来一些音乐 他们说
hey we're trying to sync this together
嘿 我们正试着把这些同步起来
with like another piece of music or I or
像是另一首音乐或者我或者
they or they want to have someone
他们或他们想要一个人
accompany and play along with it but
陪着它一起玩 但是
they need it to be in the key of F and
他们需要它在F和的基调中
not the key of G we can go okay cool we
不是G的关键 我们可以走好了 酷我们
go to effects we go to change pitch and
转到效果 我们转到改变音高
then we can change it so we can say
然后我们可以改变它 这样我们就可以说
change it from the key of G to the key
将其从G的键更改为键
of F uh-huh and then we go okay and so I
嗯 然后我们就好了 所以我
just changed the key on there now if we
刚刚把钥匙换了 如果我们
play it sounds kind of the same right
弹奏吧 听起来差不多 对吧？
but it actually is different we'll play
但实际上我们玩的是不同的
this and I'll do undoing we'll see do
这和我会做的撤销 我们会看到做的
see so it's lower the music's down
看到了吗 所以它降低了音乐的音量
sounds the same but you just changed the
听起来是一样的 但您只是更改了
key and so that's why it's kind of nice
钥匙 所以这就是为什么它很棒的原因
with this that it lets you
有了这个 它让你
oops effects change pitch it's nice if
哦 效果变了音调 如果
it lets you do that if you do know the
它允许您这样做 如果您知道
key that it's in that's why this is
关键是它在里面 这就是为什么
that's why this is pretty nice for
这就是为什么这对我来说很好
changing music and then as far as voice
不断变化的音乐 然后是声音
goes you might just use the frequencies
去吧 你可以只用频率
or the slider well I hope that made
或者滑球 我希望是这样的
sense to you go ahead and play with
对你来说是有意义的去玩吧
these different effects and you're
这些不同的效果 而你
welcome to click on some of these other
欢迎点击其中一些其他选项
ones too you'll notice they all work
你也会注意到它们都起作用了
kind of similarly sometimes it will
类似的 有时它也会
bring up a dialog box sometimes it won't
调出一个对话框有时不会
but we'll be looking to some more of
但我们将会看到更多
these in future tutorials appreciate you
在以后的教程中 这些内容将感谢您
watching go ahead and like comment
观看畅所欲言并点赞评论
subscribe leave your questions below and
订阅请在下面留下您的问题并
I hope to see you in the next video
我希望在下一个视频中看到你